- You suck, Gertrude. - You suck.
ند زدي ، ميدوني ؟ .نخير ، تو ند زدي
Yeah, I suck so bad I just skunked you.
آره ، ناجور ند زدم .اما همين الان ازت بردم
Which means, you gotta eat your pills.
.و ون باختي بايد قرصهاتو بخوري
- You're supposed to be nice to me. - I am nice to you.
.قرار بود باهام خوب رفتار كني .باهات خوب هستم
- It's not my fault you got no game. - You suck, Travis.
.اما اين تقصير من نيست تو بلد نيستي بازي كني "تو خيلي مزخرفي ، "تراوس
I know.
.ميدونم
Hey there, Travis.
"سلام ، "تراوس
- I'll check on you later. - All right.
.بعدا بهت سر ميزنم .باشه -
Travis,
... تراوس
you've been talking about seeing the world
... تو يه مدتي راجب به دنيا اطرافت صحبت ميكردي
the whole time you've been here.
.تمام وقتت رو اينجا هستي ...
Think of it as an opportunity to finally fulfill that.
.فكر كن اين فرصتيه كه عمليش بكني
- Well, then you're firing me. - Not firing, laying off.
اها ، داري اخراجم ميكني ؟ .نه ، اخراجت نميكنم .دارم يه دوره بيكار بهت ميدم
And I'm not laying you off, the state is laying you off.
.و اين دست من نيست ، تصميم مركزه
All these budget cuts.
... و مشكل اصلي بوجه ست
They're clear-cutting the part-time positions.
.كه دارن شغل هاي نيم وقت رو كاهش ميدن ...
This has nothing to do with you.
.و اصلا ه ربطي به تو نداره
My advice, Travis, go see the world.
بزار بهت يه يزي بم . برو ... دنيا رو كه اونجوري هست ببين
Get that out of your system like you've always wanted.
و از رخه ي زنديت خارجش كن .مثل هميشه كه ميخواستي
Maybe you come back, they may be hiring again.
.شايد برشتي و منم دوباره استخدامت كردم
- Home! Bring them home!
" آزادشـــون كـــــنـــيد "
- I can't believe they fired me yesterday. - Come on, man. It was a nursing home.
.باورم نميشه ديروز اخراجم كردن .بيخيال مرد ، اونجا فقط يه بيمارستان خصوصى بود
- It's a retirement home. - Yeah, that's what I said. A nursing home.
.جايي بود كه ميتونستم بازنشده بشم .آره ، ديه هموني كه فتم
- Hey, I'm carrying a sign, aren't I? - Great.
.هي ، داريم اعتراض ميكنيم خيلي خوب
Listen, not to get new-agey or nothing,
... ببين ، نمي خوام نارحت بشي اما
but I think this is something that was supposed to happen to you, you know?
.بايد اين اتفاق برات ميافتاد ...
Force you out of your comfort zone, make you mix it up a little bit.
برات فشار آوردن خارج از توانايت كار كني .كه يه مقدار برات مشكل يش آورده
- I don't need to mix it up, I need to get paid. - Get innovative then, man.
من كه نميخوام مشكلي يش بياد فقط به ول نياز دارم. يه كم بانشات باش ، مرد
Don't tell me you don't know how to do that.
. نو كه نميدوني طوري همين كاري بكني
Back in college when you were doing all that test subject shit.
سال هاي دانشاه رو به ياد بيار كه داشتي امتحان لعنتيت رو ميدادي
Selling your sperm.
همون فروختن اسرم هات
I never sold my sperm.
.من تا حالا اسرم هامو نفروختم
'Cause nobody in their right mind would pay for a piece of those genes.
ون كه هي كي نميدونه از مال من اسرم بيره
You know what?
ميدوني يه ؟
Whoever said peace rallies is where the action is, doesn't know shit.
هركي فته تظاهرات جايه .كه جنبش ها صورت ميره
- This is a fucking dyke-fest. - Not all of them.
حرف مفت زده نه همشون
- Fucking liberal pussy! - Enough.
بسه ، تمومش كن
Come on.
برو
Fucking hypocrite! Go on! Spread all your lies!
آدم عوضي
Thanks.
ممنون
- You okay? - Yeah, you?
حالت خوبه ؟ آره ... تو ي ؟
I'm all right.
آره
My dad sat me down and had me watch Red Dawn
... بابام به اجبار منو اينجا فرستاد اينجا
so that I would understand just how bad things would get
...تا متوجه بشم اه كومونيست ها رو دستير كنن...
if the Communists took over.
.اوضاع هقدر بد ميشد ...
I sort of dug that flick.
.تا حدودي موافقم
Then it was narco-traffickers, Islamo-Fascists.
س اون يه مواد فروش فاشيست بود
Bad guys just keep changing their faces and we keep going to war.
آدم بدا هميشه هره ي اصلي خودشون رو . تغيير ميدن و ما هم به جن ادامه ميدم
- And then... - We keep protesting.
.و ... به اعتراض ادامه ميديم
- United we stand. - Cheers.
.ما هم متحد ميمونيم به سلامتي
This is a big moment, Travis.
"اين خيلي لحظه ي مهميه ، "تراوس
You've just witnessed the last anti-war diatribe
تو تنها شاهدي آخرين انتقاد ... تلخي از ضد جن هستي
- the world's ever gonna hear from me. - Wow.
.كه دنيا از زبون من ميشنوه  ...
You know what I've realized? Real war's in here.
ميدوني من ي رو تجسم ميكنم ؟ .جن واقعي اينجاست
You just figured that out?
تازه بهش رسيدي ؟
No, I've known it for a while.
.نه ، يه مدتي ميشه
- But I'm finally gonna do something about it. - And what's that?
.اما ميخوام آخرش يه كاري بكنم اون ي هست ؟
I'm going to India.
.دارم ميرم هندوستان
I figure I'll do some yoga,
...تصميم رفتم يه كم يوا انجام بدم
some time in an ashram,
بعضي وتا به "آشرام" برم "آشرام : مكاني مقدس"
have sex with my guru.
.و با معلم مذهبي سكس داشته باشم
We'll both agree afterwards that it was a mistake, of course.
بهش هر دوتامون متوجه ميشيم .كه كار اشتباهي بوده
Of course.
.البته
Maybe you should go. We could meet up.
.شايد تو هم بايد بياي .ميتونيم هم دير رو ببينيم
Well, a trip like that would be a pretty penny,
خب ، اين جوري مسافرتي ... خيلي رون در مياد
- which I don't got. - Could knock over a liquor store.
.كه من انقدر ولي ندارم ميتوني مقدار از ولاتو جمع كني
I think I could come up with something slightly more legit.
.شايد بهتره يه كار بهتر انجام بدم
Such as?
مثلا ؟
You don't wanna know.
.نيازي نيست بدوني
I think I can handle it.
.فكر كنم از سش بر ميام
I mean, I think I'm intellectually limber enough.
.ميتونم كمتر ول خرج كنم
Can I see you again?
ميشه دوباره ببينمت ؟
- Michael Barris. - Travis, hey.
"مايكل بررس" "تراوس "
- Smart man. - What?
.مرد با هوش ي ؟
- You wore a suit. That's a smart move. - Yeah.
شما كت و شلوار وشيدين كار زيركانه ايه ، آره
- Just a signature will do. - Thanks, boo. Love the jacket.
.فقط امضاش كنيد مرسي . لباستون قشنه
We are strangers in a strange land, brother.
.ما غيربه هاي ، سرزمين غريب هستيم برادر
First off, what we will be doing here, for those of you that don't know,
اول از همه ، براي اونهاي كه نميدونن ...ما اينجا
will be a behavioral experiment, in which we will be simulating
بر روي رفتار شما آزمايش ميكنيم ... و اينجا يك زندان ايالتي
the conditions of life inside a state penitentiary.
.شبه سازي كرديم
Now, our only requirement is that none of you have ever served any time.
حالا ، تنها يز مهمه اينكه هي يك .از شما توي زندان نبوده باشين
If you have, we'd like to thank you for your interest,
و اه قبلا زنداني بودين ...براي توجه تون ممنونيم
but you do not fit our profile.
.اما براي كار ما مناسب نيستين
Now, we will be conducting a short series of tests in a moment,
خب، حالا يكسري آزمايش هاي ... رفتاري رو ازتون مييرم
but before we do I would just like to take a beat
اما قبل از اين كه شروع كنيم ... ...بايد يه يزي رو خدمتون عرض كنم
and let you know that although the actual experiment
شما بايد بدونين كه تمام ...  آزمايش در فضاي كاملا امنيتي و بسته
will be conducted in an utterly secure environment
.اجرا خواهد شد ...
and the participants will be safe at all times,
و همه ي شما ها در امنيت خواهين بود
some of the subjects will be deprived of their civil rights...
اما بعضي از شما از حقوق مدنى بي بهره ميشد
- It's a flying man. ...for the entire two weeks.
اين يه مرد روانه اي ... به مدت دو هفته
What's his name?
اسمش يه ؟
- Flying Man. - Now, let's get to the tests, shall we?
مرد روانه اي خب ، حالا بريم سراغ آزمايش ها
- No history of incarceration? - No.
تا حالا زندان نبودين ؟ خير
- Violence?
براي خشونت ؟
- Never? - No.
اصلا ؟ خير
- What about religion?
براي مذهب ي ؟
No? Religion's not usually a yes or no question, Mr. Hunt.
نه ؟ آقاي هانت جواب اين سوال .با "بله" و "خير" نيست
People tend to find all sorts of gray areas in which to couch their answers.
مردم رايش دارن كه بهن به .ه يزي اعتقاد دارن
Well, nothing gray here.
.خب من به يزي اعتقاد ندارم
So, how do you base your ethical decisions, then?
س ، بر ه ايه اي تصميم هاي اخلاقيه خودتون رو انجام ميدن ؟
Here.
از اينجا
I was in Boy Scouts, and drill team in high school,
من در به ي در تيم هاي اكتشاف بودم و در دبيرستان تيم حفر ناني بودم
various church groups.
و همنين توي روه هاي مذهبي متفاوت
- You were devout, then? - Still am.
س شما يه مذهبي هستيد ؟ هنوز هم هستم
And what about absolute right and wrong in the universe?
نظرتون راجب "حق و باطل" يه ؟
Well, I guess,
خب ، فكر كنم
if I believe in God, then I would have to, right?
اه به خدا اعتقاد داشته باشم س بايد "حق" رو رعايت كنم
Yeah, you know, I only got three rules,
آره ، ميدوني من سه تا قانون دارم
eat twat, smoke pot, and smile a lot.
خوردن زياد ، كشيدن مواد , خنده ي زياد
It's just a short slide-show we'd like you to watch.
اين فقط يه كوتاه هستش كه بايد ببينين
It's perfectly safe, I assure you.
كاملا با امنيته ؛ بهتون تضمين ميدم
The sheriff's deputies had escorted Duceppe back to Baton Rouge.
ارد نهباني همراه با اسكورتش " "به بوستون باز شت
I am convinced that when these animals are herded together
من متقاعد هستم هنامي كه روهي " ... از حيوانات كنار هم جمع ميشن
their instincts warn them of...
" ... غريزه ي آنها ...
... California hotel, where FBI agents...
" ... در هتل كاليفرنيا ... مامور ليس ... "
- Are you okay to move on, Mr. Hunt? - Yep. I'm good.
آقاي هانت حالتون خوبه كه ادامه بديم ؟ .بله ، من خوبم
You wouldn't have hit him.
.نبايد يارو مرد رو ميزدي
Who?
كدوم مرد ؟
The guy at the rally.
هموني كه توي تظاهرات بود
You wouldn't have hit him.
نبايد ميزديش
These knuckles, they're pristine.
بهت نمياد اهل دريري باشي
- You calling me a pussy? - Yeah.
يعني ميي ترسوم ؟ آره
- It's a compliment. - Cool.
.داشتم ازت تعريف ميكردم
I'll be gone by the time you get out, you know.
تا وقتي تو بياي بيرون من رفتم ، ميدوني كه ؟
I know.
ميدونم
Dashashwamedh Ghat, Varanasi.
هندوستان
- Varanasi. - How soon can you be there?
كي اونجا ميرسي ؟
Twelfth? Thirteenth?
دوازه ؟ سيزده
Thirteenth.
سيزده
Dashashwamedh Ghat on the 13th, 6:00 p.m.
اونجا ساعت 6 بعد از ظهر
- Hey, you made it. - Good to see you.
هي ، موفق شدي خوشحالم ميبينمت
- Yeah. - I was hoping I'd have someone to talk to.
آره . اميد وارم بودم يكي بياد باهاش حرف بزنم
I can't help but think that this says something about us.
نميتونم كمك كنم ، اما فكر كنم اين يه يزي راجب ما داره ميه
I think it says we need money.
آره ، ميه ما به ول نياز داريم
- Sorry. - Hey, how's it going?
ببخشيد ه خبرا ؟
- It's the beginning. - Game on.
.شروع شد
So let's move on to the topic of women. What's that word mean to you?
خب اجازه بده راجب كلمه ي زن صحبت كنيم اين كلمه ه معني برات داره ؟
Women? What?
زن ؟ ي ؟
Everything on God's green earth
... يزهاي كه خدا روي زمين خلق كرده
and possibly beyond what's been discovered in our universe yet?
فراتر از يزهايه كه ما توي اين جهان يدا كرديم
I don't know.
نميدونم
Hey, chickenshit, we got a draft!
هي ، مرغ نديده . كار داريم
Didn't you hear me, chickenshit?
صدامو ميشوني ؟
We got a draft. Close the window!
نجره رو ببند
I fell asleep. How far did we drive?
خوابم مياد ، هقدر راه اومديم ؟
This is a fucking spot.
عجب جاي نديه
Gentlemen, they're waiting inside.
.آقايون ، داخل منتظرن
You mind if I just grab my bag? There's some stuff in there that I need.
اجازه ميدي خودم كيفم رو بيارم ؟ .ون وسايلي توشه كه بهشون  نياز دارم
You'll have everything you need inside.
.هر ي بخواي ، اون تو هست
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
عصر بخير ، آقايون
The next two weeks will be a new experience for you.
در طول اين دو هفته تجربه ي .تازه ي رو خواهيد شيد
Now as I said before, some of you will have no civil rights.
همون جوري كه فتم امكانش هست حقوق مدني نداشته باشين
Do not underestimate that.
.س ازش شم وشي نكند
If any of you wanna leave, now is your last chance.
اه هر يك از شما ميخواد بره .الان آخرين فرصته
No?
هي كس ؟
Good.
خوبه
Again, your safety is our number one priority.
دوباره ميم ، امنيت شما .اولين اولويت ماست
If there is any violence, any at all,
... ار در هر شرايطي ، اتفاق بيافته
the experiment will be immediately terminated.
.سريعا آزمايش متوقف ميشه ...
Clear?
متوجه شندين ؟
Now, when I call your name, please stand.
لصفا اسم هر كسي رو صدا زدم بلند شه
Dernier, Bosch,
"درنير " ،  "بواش"
Helweg, Sandberg,
"هيلو" ،"سنبر"
Chase, and Barris.
"يس" و "برس"
Good.
خوبه
So the rest of you, please stand up and follow the yellow line.
خب ، بقيه شما بلند شين و اين خط .زرد رو دنبال كنيد
- Later, pal. - Good luck, gentlemen. And I thank you.
فعلا ، رفيق موفق باشين. ازتون ممنونم
So what do you think, Girl Scouts? Prisoners or guards?
خب ه فكري كردي ؟ زنداني يا نهبان ؟
I think we just got our answer.
فكر كنم جوابمون رو رفتيم
Nothing is to come or go from the cell block.
هي يزي داخل يا خارج نميشه
Nothing from the outside world.
هي يزي
If you look in your lockers, you will see a printout with the five rules
اه قفسه هاتون رو ناه كنيد نج قانون زندان رو خواهيد ديد
that the prisoners are to follow at all times.
كه بايد زندانين در هر شرايطي رعايت كنن
Please read them aloud with me.
لطفا با صداي بلند با من بخونين
"Rule number one:
... قانون اول
"Prisoners must eat three meals a day and all food must be consumed.
زندانين بايد سه وعده " "كامل در روز غذا بخوند
"Two: There will be 30 minutes of rec daily.
"دو : " هر روز سي دقيقه فيلم ظبط ميشه
"Three: Prisoners are allowed only in prisoner-designated areas.
سه : "زندانيان فقط حق رفت ".و آمد در محيط زندان را دارند
"Four: Prisoners must speak only when spoken to.
هار : "زندانيان فقط در مواقع ".نياز ، بايد صحبت كنند
"And five: Prisoners must not touch the guards under any circumstances."
نج : "زندانيان در هي شرايطي ".حق لمس كردن نهبانان را ندارند
Those that break the rules must be punished commensurately.
كساني كه قانون ها را اعايت نكند .به همان اندازه مجازات خواهند شد
What does "commensurate" mean?
به همان اندازه" يعني ي؟"
This experiment is not about individuals.
اين آزمايش مختص يك فرد خاص نيست
If any one person leaves, it's over.
ار كسي اينجا رو ترك كنه ، تمومه
If a prisoner does break the rules,
... اه زنداني قانوني رو رعايت نكنه
you will have 30 minutes to choose proper disciplinary action.
شما سي دقيقه وقت دارين مجازات متناسب را انجام بدين
If you fail to do so, that red light will come on,
و ار مجازات را انجام ندين ، اون ... راغ قرمز روشن خواهد شد
the experiment will be terminated, and you will not get paid.
و آزمايش تموم ميشه و شما ... .هم هي ولي دريافت نميكنيد
- What did you say? - You either maintain strict order,
ي فتي ؟ ... يا به دستوري كه دادم عمل ميكني
or you don't get paid.
.يا ولي يرت نمياد ...
I will see you in two weeks.
دو هفته ديه ملاقاتتون ميكنم
- Sorry, man. - For what?
شرمنده براي ي ؟
- All this. - Don't sweat it.
براي همه ي بيخيال
All right, turn around. Gotta do the front.
خوبه ديه ، بررد
What? Nobody else had to turn around.
ي ؟ هي كي روشو برنردوند
What's the problem, Boy George,
مشكليت يه ؟
you afraid we gonna see that you got no dick?
ميترسي ببينيم كه آلات تناسلي  نداري ؟
- Fuck you. - Hey, man. Quit being a fag, huh?
عوضي هي مرد ، بيخيال
All right, girls. Everyone on the line!
.خيلي خب ، خانونها همه ي توي يه صف
- Which one? - I don't know.
كدوم صف ؟ نميدونم
That one. That line.
اون يكي
- How you doing? - Gotta be honest,
بايد رو راست باشم
you guys are the most suck-ass guards I've ever seen.
شما نهبان ها مزخرف ترين نهبان هاي هستين كه تا حالا ديدم
Yeah, well, you can blow me and the entire state of Kentucky.
آره ، خب تو ميتوني من و كنتاكي" رو با حرفات بتركوني"
Kentucky?
كينتاكي ؟
All right, look, we gotta stop fucking around
خيلي خب ، ديه مسخره بازي بسه
or they might end this thing before it even begins.
ورنه قبل از اينكه شروع بشه ، تموم ميشه
I didn't come all the way out here not to get paid.
من اين همه راه رو نيومدم كه جيب خالي برردم
"From now on inmates will be addressed only by their inmate numbers."
.از اين به بعد زنداني ها با شماره صدا ميكنيم
That's awesome.
عاليه
The only other thing that you girls need to know
و تنها يز ديه اي كه شما ... بايد بدونين اين كه
is, "Prisoners will find cell assignments attached to each cell."
هر كدوم از شما سلول مشخصي دارين
- Are we supposed to do that? - Yes, Tinker Bell.
بايد همين كاري بكنيم ؟ آره ، استاد
- Now? - Yes.
همين الان ؟ آره
Now run along. Run along, find your homes.
.حالا راه برو و جاتو يدا كن
- Okay. - Going.
باشه
Hey, Travis.
سلام ، من تراوسم
Seventeen.
.هفده
Seventy-seven.
هفتاد و هفت
Wow, I feel dangerous just wearing this outfit.
يه جور احساس خطر توي اين لباس ها دارم
- You look dangerous. - Oh, yeah.
آره ، خطرناك به نظر مياي
Yeah, you are massively messing with me, right?
آره ، داري به شدت سركارم ميزاري ؟
- No. - No?
نه نه ؟
- Benjy Putterman. - How you doing? Travis.
بينجي وترمن تراوس
Novelist.
رمان نويس هستم
- Novelist, huh? - Graphic novelist, actually.
در واقعه رمان نويس مصور
- Comics. - Graphic novels.
كيمك نويس ؟ رمان نويس مصور
Oh, my God, I'm gonna get so much material from this place.
خداي من ، سوژه هاي خيلي توي ميتونم از اين مكان بيرم
- This is ripping! - Yeah.
!اينجا خيلي عاليه آره
Ripping.
عاليه
So, what drew you to this experiment?
خب ، ه يزي تو رو به اين آزمايش جذب كرد ؟
Cash-dollars.
ول
My mother.
به خاطر مادرم
It was her idea?
نظر مادرت بود ؟
She broke her hip,
... لنش شكسته
I needed to pay the rent.
.بايد ول جور كنم ...
Do you live with your mother?
با مادرت زندي ميكني ؟
Yes.
بله
And how old are you?
و مادرت ند سالشه ؟
Forty-two.
هل و دو
So, what drew you to this experiment, Mr. Chase?
خب ، ي شما رو به اين آزمايش جذب كرد ؟
Pussy. Pussy drew me to the experiment.
زن ها ، زن ها منو به اين آزمايش جذب كرد
It's a male-only experiment, Mr. Chase.
آقاي يس اين آزمايش فقط مخصوص مرد هاست
It's the pussy I'm gonna get with the 14 grand once I'm done.
خب همين به خاطر اينكه اون زنيكه هارده هزار دلار ول ميخواد
How many sexual partners have you had?
ند تا شريك جنسي داريد ؟
I lost track when I was, like, 17.
تعدادشو دقيق نميدونم ، شايد 17 تا
Were they male or female?
زن هستن يا مرد ؟
Female.
زن
So, what drew you to this experiment, Mr. Nix?
خب ، آقاي نكس ، ي شما رو به اين آزمايش جذب كرده ؟
I'm just trying to make an honest buck, man.
ميخوام ول حلال در بيارم
Escape.
.فرار
- Flying Man? - No.
مرد روانه اي ؟ نه
You guys go ahead.
.شما اول بريد
Oh, hell no. These knees are busted.
.نه ، بيخيال زانوهام داغون شدن
Hey, how about it, redwood? Throw it down?
هي تو ي ؟ بيرش
- Wait. - Oh, my God. Is he okay?
وايسا ، خداي من حالت خوبه ؟
- I'm sorry. - Fuck.
ببخشيد مرد
- Bosch, you all right? - I'm all right.
بوش ، تو خوبي ؟ آره خوبم
- Let's get you out of here. - I thought he was looking.
بيا از اينجا بريم بيرون
- Come on. - I did.
بيخيال
- You all right, big man. You all right. - It's all right. It was an accident.
هيي نبود ، فقط يه اتفاق بود
It's all right.
هيي نيست
What the fuck was that guy thinking, huh?
اون ياور باخودش ي فكر كرده ؟
I'm okay. I'm okay. He didn't mean it.
.من خوبم ، اون هي منظوري نداشت
- Sure you're all right? - It's just a bloody nose.
مطمئني خوبي ؟ آره ، فقط خون دماغه سادست
Let's just go back to work. Please.
.خواهش ميكنم ، بررديم سركار
I don't know.
.نميدونم
- I think we gotta do something. - What are you talking about?
.فكر كنم بايد ما هم يه كاري بكنيم راجب ي داري حرف ميزني ؟
I'm talking about rule number five.
.دارم راجب قانون شماره نج حرف ميزنم
Prisoners are not supposed to touch us.
.زنداني ها نميتونن به ما دست بزنن
Well, technically, he didn't touch us. The ball did.
.خب ، اون كه منو نزد ، تو منو زد
Look at your face, man.
.خودتو ببين ، مرد
I mean, we all heard what they said. We gotta keep the order.
.ما هممون شنيديم كه اونها ي فتن .بايد قوانين رو اجرا كنيم
Respond commensurately.
"به همون اندازه واكنش نشون بديم"
They saw it. They know it was an accident.
اونا خودشون ديدن. ميدونن .فقط يه اتفاق بوده
- I agree. - Are you sure about that?
موافقم ميدونم تو مطمئني
Look, I just don't want that light to come on in 30 minutes
ببين فقط دوست ندارم اون راغ ... سي دقيقه ديه روشن بشه
because we didn't do what we were supposed to do.
.ون كاري رو كه بايد ميكرديم رو نكرديم ...
- I got 14 grand on the line. - Yeah, we all got 14 grand on the line.
من به اون ول نياز دارم آره ، ما به اون ول نياز داريم
Come on.
بيخيال
We're not talking about crucifying the man here.
ما كه نمي خوايم به صليب بكشونمشون
The word's commensurate.
فقط به طور متناسب
Which means,
... كه يعني
if what the man did was small potatoes,
اه اون مرد كاري نايزي انجام داده
we respond in kind.
س ما هم همين جوري ميكنيم
Small potatoes for small potatoes.
به كار نايز در مقابل يه كار نايز
Either that,
... يا
or we wait till that light goes on.
بايد صبر كنيم تا اون راغ روشن بشه ...
Push-ups, ten.
ده تا شٌنا برو
Do them now.
همين حالا
I just need a little civility, that's all.
من فقط بايد يه كم يا شعور تر بودم
It was an accident.
فقط يه تصادف بود
This is not a fucking negotiation. Do the push-ups.
ما كه با هم معامله نميكنيم شٌنا برو
Just a little civility, brother. Just a little.
فقط كمي نزاكت ،بردار
All right, everyone, ten push-ups.
خيلي خب ، همه ده تا شٌنا برن
You heard the man. Let's go.
شما كه شنيدن ، زود باشين
Do it! Come on, do it!
زود باش انجامش بده
Yeah, follow your little brother.
آره ، به حرف بردار مويكت وش كن
There we are.
آفرين
Count them out.
بشمارين
What did that tell you, huh? Tater Tots for Tater Tots.
ي بهت فتم ؟
And you, you ought to be a cop, dude.
و تو رفيق بايد يه ليس باشي
- Looked more like a drill sergeant to me. - Yeah.
به نظر من بيشتر به يه سرهن ميخوره آره
Like that guy out of Full Metal Jacket.
"مثل همون مرده توي "فول متال جكت "اشاره به فيلم فول متال جكت"
I'm almost embarrassed for them, to be honest.
يه مقدار دلم براشون سوخت
You know, stepping and fetching like that.
ميدوني ، شريك بودن توي همين كاري
Has it been 30 minutes yet?
هنوز نيم ساعت نشه ؟
Just.
را
I guess we got our verdict.
فكر كنم درست كاري كرديم
I'm not mad, you know?
... من از دست اونها
At them.
عصباني نيستم ...
They keep making us do push-ups like this, we'll be all swoll.
اونها ما رو مجبور كردن شنا بريم
All of us are.
و همه رو خيس عرق كردن
You know, get paid and get in shape.
و ول مييرن خوش هيكل ميشن
- You got a girl, 17? - No.
دوست دختر داري ؟ نه
What about you?
تو ي ؟
- I'm at the start of something. - Yeah?
دارم شروع ميكنم آره ؟
Me too. Feels good, doesn't it?
. منم احساس خوبي داره ، نه ؟
- Good and bad. - Mine's a barista.
هم خوبه ، هم بد
Wouldn't think a guy like me could pull a barista, would you?
فكر نميكردي يكي مثل من دوست داشته باشه ، مه نه ؟
What exactly do you write, anyway?
دقيقا ، تو ه جوري رمان نويسي هستي ؟
- Comics. - Graphic novels.
كميك . رمان نويس مصور
Yeah, Flying Man's my next big launch.
آره ، مرد روانه اي روژهي بعديه
- Flying Man? - Yep.
مرده رنده ؟ آره
The man who flies.
مردي كه رواز ميكنه
- What's he do besides fly? - See that?
ديه ه كارهاي ميتونه به غير از رواز بكنه ؟
What you just said, "What else he do besides fly?"
تو ي فتي ، ه كار ديه اي ميتونه بكنه ؟
That's how jaded people have become. We're talking about flying here.
و اين يزهي كه مردم بي سليقه بهش رسيدن ما داريم راجب رواز صحبت ميكنيم
Like a human being, actually flying.
مثل يك آدم ، كه واقعا رواز ميكنه
And no cape, nothing. Just flying, you know?
بودن هي شنلي ، هيي فقط رواز ميكنه ، رفتي ؟
Like you or me in this cell just kind of taking off
درست مثل من و تو ، توي اين سلول
like nothing could limit us. Like we could just go, go, go.
كه هيي نميتونه مانع ما بشه و ما ميتونيم همين جوري بريم و بريم و بريم
Tell me, honestly, who is not gonna want to read that?
بهم بو ، كي نمي خواد همنين يز رو نخونه ؟
I shouldn't be talking about this anyway. My agent would kill me if he knew I was.
من نبايد راجب اين باهاتون صحبت كنم اه مديرعاملم بفهمه منو ميكشه
- You got an agent, huh? - Yeah, couple.
تو مدير داري ؟ آره ، ندتا
How you like that, 77?
تو ي هفتاد و هفت ؟
Looks like we got a heavy hitter in the box with us.
مثل اين كه با يه آدم كله نده هم سلول هستيم
Yeah, we do.
آره
9:00, ladies! Lights out!
خانوم ها! راغ ها خاموش
- Really, come on. - What?
همين ؟ بيخيال ي ؟
- What is it? - Move along, fuck-butt.
اين يه ؟ برو م شو
Yum, yum, come on, people. Move along!
زود باشن ، حركت كنين
Hey, hey, hey. You gotta clean your plate.
هي ، هي . بايد همشو بخوري
Come on, man. That's not gonna happen.
بيخيال مرد ، مرد . همين اتفاقي نميوفته
What are you? Spokesman for the union now?
تو ي هستي ؟ سخنو اجتماع ؟
Look, nobody's trying to be difficult.
ببين ، هي كسي نميخواد مشكلي يش بياد
We'll eat everything else, just not that.
ما همه يزي ميخوريم ، به غير از اين
I mean, look at it. It literally might be dog shit.
يه ناهي بهش بنداز مثل ه س ميمونه
It's beans. Come on, eat them.
لوبياست . زود باشين بخورين
Come on, guys.
بيخيال رفقا
It's not like I'm being unreasonable here, right?
من كه نيستم اينجا زود ميم ، درسته ؟
I mean, we got rules, okay?
منظورم اين كه ما قانون داريم
Rule number one: You gotta clean your plate.
قانون اول : شماها بايد تا آخر غذاتون رو بخوريد
Rule number six says, "You gotta eat dog shit."
قانون ششم ميه : بايد ه س بخوري
It's not dog shit.
اين ه س نيست
It's dog shit.
را هست
Well, that's too bad. 'Cause you gotta eat it anyway.
.خب ، خيلي بد شد ون به هر حال بايد بخوريدش
Okay, I'm gonna just... Oh, my God. My dog shit!
... باشه ، من ميخوام !واي خداي من . ه سم
You fucking shit. Out of there.
.تو يه عوضي هستي
Look, okay, memo to Adolf, uniform's not real. Okay, baby?
باشه خودتو كنترل كن اين لباست واقعي نيست باشه ؟
Hey, Moulin Rouge, you gotta eat it.
هي ، بايد بخوريش
Nobody's leaving here until their plates are clean.
هي كسي اينجا رو ترك نميكنه مر اينكه غذاشو كامل بخوره
You heard the man, huh?
شنيدي كه ؟
The word is clean.
"بايد تا آخر بخوري"
- Clean? Is that the word? - Yeah.
تا آخر بخوريم ؟ آره
Now it's clean.
.حالا خوردم
He just earned you guys some more push-ups.
اون فقط براتون دردسر درست كرد ندتا ديه شنا بريد
Push-ups. You heard the man! Push-ups!
شنيدي كه ، شنا برين
I'll give you push-ups. Push this up!
وايسا الان شنا رو بدن نشون ميدم
Complete wrong move, ass-licker.
حركت اشتباهي رفتي , احمق
Step back!
!برردين عقب
- You shouldn't have done that! - Keep it up, girls. Get it out of your system.
نبايد همين كاري ميكردين
That's right, you goose-stepping pussy!
خيلي خوبه ، شما ها دارين عقب ميكشين
I will see you girls tonight.
امشب ميبينمتون
Feel the wrath of Flying Man!
!خشم مرد روانه اي رو احساس كن
Flying Man?
مرد روانه اي ؟
Yeah.
آره
This is our house, bitches! This is our house!
اينجا خونه ي ماست عوضي ها
Only reason, only fucking reason they did that
... تنها دليلي كه اين كار رو كردن اين بود
was 'cause they knew they weren't gonna get their asses kicked.
.كه مي دونستن ما باهاشون درير نميشيم ...
You take away someone's fear of getting punched in the fucking mouth,
ترس يكي رو بايد با يه مشت درست و حسابي از ببين ببري
all of a sudden, they're the biggest cocksuckers
و اون به آدم ترسو تبديل ميشه
on the fucking planet.
.و ازت اطاعت ميكنه
That may be true, but the rules are the rules.
.شايد درست باشه . اما قانون ، قانونه
We don't use violence.
.ما از خوشنت استفاده نميكنيم
Well, we obviously gotta do something.
.خب ، بايد ما يه كاري بكنيم
I mean, we are being tested just as much as they are.
منظورم اين كه ، ما هم داريم .مثل اونها آزمايش ميشيم
They made me look like a fucking pussy is what they did.
اونا منو مثل يه تيكه آشغال كردن
Yeah.
آره
I got an idea.
.يه نظر دارم
I pledged for a fraternity once.
يه بار براي انجمن برادان ول دادم
And during Hell Week, the brothers,
و در مدت اون هفته
they would break down our will.
و اونها خواسته هاي مارو اجرا نميكردن
They would try to humble us for the initiation that was gonna come.
اونها ما رو براي تفكر و خلاقيتمون تحقير ميكردن
I mean, the rules, they were pretty much the same as here.
قانون اونجا هم دقيقا مثل اينجا بود
I mean, they couldn't hurt us.
منظورم اين كه ، نميتونستن به ما صدمه بزنن
But they could do something much worse,
اما ميتونستن از اون بدتر بكنن
they could humiliate us.
اونا ميتونستن ما رو تحقير بكنن
That's what we have to do.
و اين كاريه كه ما هم بايد بكنيم
Is we have to humiliate them.
ما هم بايد اونها رو تحقير كنيم
What? What are you doing?
ه خبره ؟ ي شده ؟
- What the hell is the matter with you? - That is for inciting them.
ه مرت شده ؟ اين واسه اينكه تجريك بشي
- What? What are you talking about? - Shut up.
ي داري ميي ؟ خفه شو
You need to shut up. All right?
بايد خفه بشي ، حاليت شد ؟
There will be no more incidents
... ديه اتفاقي مثل امروز
like there was today.
نخواهد افتاد ...
Is that understood?
مفهوم شد ؟
I said, is that understood?
فتم ، مفهوم شد ؟
- Yes.
بله ، بله
Yes, what? 'Cause I can't hear you.
بله ، ي ؟ نميشنونم ي ميين
- Yes, sir!
بله قربان
Who's the bitches now, bitches?
حالا كي عوضيه ، عوضيها ؟
Great job, guys. Great job.
كارت خوب بود
- Dude, I... - Great job.
كارت حرف نداشت
- Nice speech. - Good job, good job.
سخن رانيه خوبي بود كارت خوب بود
I'll catch up later.
بعدا ميبينمتون
Excuse me? Excuse me?
ببخشيد ؟
I'm having heat flashes. I think my blood sugar is low.
دماي بدنم بالا رفته . قند خونم كم شده
Capote, just shut the fuck up, okay?
لصف كن خفه شو ، باشه ؟
- What are you talking about, man? - I'm having low blood sugar.
داري ي ميي ، مرد ؟ . من مرض قند خون داريم
If I gotta say "Shut the fuck up" one more time...
بايد يه بار ديه بم خفه شو
You all right?
حالت خوبه ؟
Okay, everybody's had their fun.
خيلي خب ، همه حال خودشون رو كردن
I'm gonna suggest
... من ميخوايم يه يشنهاد بدم
that we act like gentlemen for the rest of the way.
ما اين يازده روز مانده رو ... مطابق قانون هاي وضع شده
That we play by the rules
... مثل آدم هاي با شخصيت  ...
these last 11 days.
باهاتون رفتار ميكنيم
And everybody can go home happily with their money.
و همه ميتونن با خوشنودي با ولشون برردن خونه
How's that sound?
نظرتون يه ؟
Where is 51?
نجاه و يك ، كجاست ؟
Let's go.
اشو بريم
I need sugar.
من به قند نياز دارم
Look, diabetic. Says he's diabetic on his application.
ببين ، اون يارو ديابت داره
So he needs insulin, that's what it is.
س انسولين ميخواد
No, no, no. Look. It says he regulates it through diet.
نه ، نه ، نه ببين اينجا نوشته اون يه رژيم خاص داره
Yeah, man, it's in his own words.
.آره ، مرد اين حرف رو خودش زده
He's the one that filled this out.
خودش اين رو ر كرده
This is not a big deal. It's not.
.خيلي مهم نيست
I mean, my fucking grandma has basically the same thing,
ببين ، مادر بزر عوضيه من ... هم اين جوري بود اما
and she just gets moody in between meals.
.و فقط بين وعده هاي غذايش عصبي ميشد
Trust me, this is not a big deal.
باور كن ، هييش نميشه
Fifty-one, you need to get up.
نجاه و يك ، از جات بلند شو
Let's go, come on. Get up.
زود باش ، اشو
Hey, I wanna do this.
هي ، ميخوام همين كاري بكنم
I do. I just need a Twix bar.
من به "تويكس "نياز دارم "تويكس : نوعي شكلات"
There's one in my bag if you can find it.
يكي توي كيفم هست
Twix bar. Is that what you wanna eat?
تويكس ، ميخواي تويكس بخوري ؟
Get him up. Get him up. Come on. Come on!
زود باشه ، بلندش كنين
- Are you kidding me? - You're all right.
حالت خوبه
- Hey, why don't you let the man be? - You know the rules, 77.
هي را نزاشتي 51 بياد توي صف ؟ تو كه قوانين رو ميدوني
All prisoners must participate in rec.
همه ي زنداني ها بايد توي فيلم در حال ضبط باشن
And you do not address me unless I have spoken to you first.
و تا من يزي نفتم ، تو حق نداري يزي بي
The man... Look at him.
... ناهش كن
The man can't do it.
اين مرد نميتونه اين كار رو بكنه
You do understand that this is a prison experiment, right?
متوجه هستي كه ، اين يك آزمايش شبيه سازي زندانه
Yes.
بله
And you do understand the roles that we've been given?
و متوجه ي قوانين هستي كه ما اونها رو داديم ؟
- Obviously. - You are a prisoner.
ظاهرا شما ها زنداني هستين
You don't give orders, we give orders.
شما دستوري نميدين ما دستور ميديم
Have I made myself completely clear to you now?
حالا كاملا روشن شدي ؟
Let the man lie down.
بزار اين مرد استراحت بكنه
Do I need to escalate matters right now?
يعني لازمه حتما با تندي رفتار كنم ؟
Is that what I should do?
واقعا لازمه ؟
What is that supposed to mean?
منظورت يه ؟
It means that you won't shut up.
منظورم اين كه خفه شي
And I am trying to figure out how I'm supposed to deal with that.
و دارم سعي ميكنم كه مشكل رو حل كنم
- Why don't you try being rational? - How is this for rational?
را نميخواي منطقي باشي ؟ الان منطقيم ؟
Do I look rational now? Do I?
الان منطقي هستم ؟ هستم ؟
You hit me and the experiment is over.
اه منو بزني آزمايش تعطيل ميشه
You know that and I know that.
خودت هم ميدوني و منم ميدونم
Easy now, brother. Come on.
بيخيال ، برادر بريم
Okay. It's okay.
خيلي خب
All right, everyone, back in their cell.
همه برردن توي سلولشون
Let's go, guards! Get them back in their cells!
برين بررد توي سلولت
- Let's go. - Get in!
برين داخل
What do you think they want from us?
را به اين آزمايش اومدي ؟
Throw some animals in a cage
الان مثل خيون ها توي قفس هستيم
and you get to find out which one of us is gonna be the lions
و بايد ببينيم كدومون "شير" هستيم
and which ones are gonna get gut.
"و كدومون مثل "بره
I like to think we're slightly higher on the evolutionary chain than monkeys.
دوست داريم فكر كنم ما نسل برتر از ميمون ها هستيم
It don't matter how evolved you think we are.
برام مهم نيست كه ما ه قدر برتر هستيم
You lock up any animal long enough and the strong's gonna eat the weak.
آخرش به اين نتيجه ميرسيم اوني كه قويه ، ضعيف رو ميخوره
That's just the way it is.
و هميشه همين جوريه
You learn that in prison, 17?
مه قبلا زندان بودي ؟
- You must think I'm somebody else, slick. - No.
نه
Just that tattoo you got there is an Aryan tat,
... فقط براي اون خالي كه داري
so I figured, you know, you probably got that in the pen.
فكر كرديم شايد زندان بودي
Expert in the penitentiary system, are you, boy?
مه تو قبلا توي زندان بودي ، به ؟
I just watch a lot of Discovery Channel.
نه فقط زيادي شبكه هاي علمي ناه ميكنم
You will not interfere with my ability to make a paycheck.
تو نبايد ري توي كارم بندازي ، تا بتونم ولم رو بيرم
You understand?
حاليت شد ؟
We're cool. No sweat.
آره
So, what were you in for anyway?
حالا ، جرمت ي بود ؟
- Did you really just ask me that? - Yeah. I just asked you that.
واقعا ميخواي بدوني ؟ آره
- You better pump your brakes, boy. - Oh, yeah?
داري زياد تر از حدت ميري ؟ راستي ؟
- Why's that? - Lf you don't start respecting the guards,
مه يه ؟ ... تو به نهبان ها احترام نميزاي
you're gonna have a serious problem.
و اين برا دردسر بزري ميشه ...
- They're not guards. - No, they're guards all right.
اونها نهبان نيست نه ، هستن
And them up there, they're getting exactly what they want.
و اونها اون بالا ، دارن همون يزي رو كه ميخوانبه دست ميارن
I suggest you stop protecting your friend.
من ميم بهتره ديه از رفيقت حمايت نكني
What's right is right, man.
هري كه درست باشه ، درسته
Last thing a man wants to be in the pen is right.
تنها يزي مهم براي يه زنداني حقشه
Dudes, they...
رفيق ، اونا
They start digging in and getting all righteous then.
اونها دارن همه كاري مكنن ... كه رحم و مروتو از ببين ببرن
That only leads to one place. Go along to get along, man.
و اين تنها برات يه راه اره ميزاره " باهاشون همكار كن تا اين وضع تموم بشه "
Whatever fire you got in your belly, you're best to let it go.
هريزي كه اعصابتو بهم ريخت بهتره ، بهش بي توجه ي بكني
Trust me.
بهم اعتماد كن
Let it go.
بي خيالش شو
All I know
تنها يزي كه ميدونم
is homie lost his shit back there.
سر اون ايين غوغا كردي
- It was just a show. - For you, maybe.
فقط يه نمايش بود شايد براي تو بوده باشه
- Half those fuckers, they were ready to go. - They weren't gonna do anything.
اما نصف اون آشغال ها ميخوام آزمايش رو ترك كنن ، بايد يه كاري بكنيم
How well do you know them?
هقدر اون ها رو ميشناسي ؟
The assholes outnumber us, for one.
... اونها از ما بيشتر بودن
If they wanted to take the advantage, they could.
اه ميخواستن يه ما حمله كنن ميتونستن
Us out here in the middle of fucking nowhere, we're on our own.
و ما الان تنهاي تنها وسط ناكجا آباديم
The experimenters, they wouldn't let anything happen.
اين آزمايش ، نميزاره دست از ا خطا كنن
How well do you know them?
تو ه قدر اونها رو ميشناسي ؟
Seventy-seven, he's the ringleader.
هفتاد و هفت ، اون سردسته شونه
Either way, if it keeps going like this, someone's gonna throw down.
تازه ، اه اين جوري ادمه بدن با هم درير ميشيم
Look, guys, guys. If anyone gets hurt, this experiment is over.
اه كسي صدمه ببينه ، آزمايش تعطيل ميشه
None of us will get paid.
و هي كسي ولي يرش نمياد
Well, we gotta put the clamps on this thing once and for all then.
س بايد واسه يه بار هم شده كار درست و حسابي انجام بديم
What're you thinking?
داري به ي فكر ميكني ؟
You wanna know how to reach these guys?
ميدوني طوري بايد به اين آدم ها نفوذ كني ؟
How?
طور ؟
You scare 'em.
بايد بترسونيشون
Comfortable?
راحتي ؟
Helweg?
... هيلو
Come on...
زود باش
The prisoners, they listen to you.
زنداني ها ، بهت وش ميدن
For some reason they look to you like you're the leader.
بنا به دلايلي بهت به عنوان رهبرشون نات ميكنن
I got news for you.
ند تا خبر برات دارم
In here,
... تو اينجا
you're the leader of shit.
رهبر آشغال ها هستي ...
This place, it belongs to us.
اين جا ، مال ماست
It belongs to us.
مال ما
Hey, there are all kinds of things that we could do to you
هي ، اينجا هر بلاي كه بخوايم ميتونيم ... سرت بياريم
So, do we have the proper respect
... حالا احترام ذاشتن به رئيست
for authority now?
رو ياد رفتي ؟
Fuck you, you sick fuck.
لعنت به تو ، آشغال عوضي
This stuff is going right through me.
اين لعنتي منو مجبور ميكنه " منظور از مشروب خورده شده "
- Saddle up, gentlemen! - Fuck!
آقايون شما هم بفرمايد
You want to send a message?
ميخواي يغام بدي ؟
Then send a message. Saddle up.
س بو ، زود باشين ديه
Saddle up!
شما هم مشغول شين
You okay?
حالت خوبه ؟
That was colossally fucked up.
كار باحالي بود
I mean, you are shit-ass nuts, you know that?
ميدوني خيلي كله خري ؟
And that's a good thing, Barris.
و اين همون نكته ي خوبشه ، بررس
The light, it didn't come on. They saw it, and it's not coming on.
راغ قرمز روشن نشد. يعني اونا ما رو ديدن
We did what we did, we sent a message, but it never leaves this place.
ما كاري رو كرديم ، كه بايد ميكريم بهشون يغام داديم. اما هي وقت اينجا رو ترك نميكنن
I got something to say.
. ميخوام يه يزي بم
If anything happens like that again, anything at all,
... اه هر اتفاقي دوباره ، مثل اين بيوفته
I'm out of here.
من ميرم ...
You make a unilateral decision like that,
... تو ميخواي تصميم يك جانبه بيري
it could cost the rest of us 100 grand.
كه اين براي ما خيلي رون تموم ميشه
I don't care, sir.
برام مهم نيست ، قربان
Let it go.
بيخيال
Scenario.
متن موضوع
Someone harms someone you love. Rapes them, kills them.
يك نفر ، اوني رو كه دوست داري آزار ميده ، بهش تجاوز ميكنه ، ميكشدش
The law fails to prosecute.
و قانون هم كاري نميكنه
This person is free. There is absolutely nothing you can do.
و مجرم آزاده . تو هم هي كاري از دستت بر نمياد
- Would you consider that justice? - I don't think on those terms.
تو اينو عدالت ميدوني ؟ تا حالا به نين شرايطي فكر نكردم
Justice is what keeps us safe as a society. Ordered.
عدالت يزهي كه ما رو در امنيت قرار ميده
Well, justice is... Well, it starts wars. An eye for an eye for an eye.
خب ، عدالت .... جن رو شروع ميكنه . و شم در مقابل شم
It takes a turning of the cheek for this species to evolve.
كه باعث از بين رفتن افكار ميشه و همنين نوع و يشرفت بشر
So, you're the one who knows what it's going to take
... خب تو ميدوني ه اتفاقي براي
for the human species to evolve.
.نوع بشر و يشرفتش ميوفته
Just regurgitating what people a lot smarter than me have been saying
فقط اونيزي رو دارم بازو ميكنم كه از دهن مردم باهوش ميشنوم
Hey.
هي
Look what I found. Take it. That ought to boost your blood sugar.
ببين ي يدا كردم. بخورش يه مقداري قند خوندت رو بالا ميبره
No, it won't.
نه ، نميبره
Yeah, there's a lot of carbohydrates in there.
را ، كربوهيدارت زيادي توش داره
It's like the world's cheapest bread. It's going to turn to sugar. Trust me.
تصور كن ارزون ترين نان دنياست بهم اعتماد كن توي شكمت قند ميشه
Yeah, it won't turn to insulin, though.
آره ، اما انسولين نميشه
I thought you didn't need insulin.
فكر ميكردم به انسولين نياز نداري
Fibbed.
دروغ فتم
If they wouldn't let me bring it down here, I figured I could tough it out.
اه اجازه ندان كيفم رو بيارن فكر كنم اوضاع خيلي بدتر ميشه
Jesus Christ.
خدايا
- Benjy... - Fifty-one.
... نجاه و يك
Listen, you can't play around with this. I got to let them know immediately.
ببين ، من نميزام تو همين جوري بخوابي بايد هره سريعتر بهشون بم
I mean, they need to know. I got to get you out of here.
بايد از اين موضوع باخبر بشن بايد از اينجا ببرمت بيرون
No.
نـه
You don't understand. You could die.
متوجه نيستي . امكان داره بميره
Not if I get the insulin.
. اه بهم انسولين برسه ، نميميرم
Why are you doing this?
را داري اين كار رو ميكني ؟
Flying Man is a fraud.
مرد روانه اي ... فقط يه دورغ بود
Don't say that.
اين جوري نو
Yeah. It's stupid. It's a stupid, shitty, fat lie. Just like me.
آره ، اين احمقانست . يه دورغ
He's just a man that flies.
اون مرديه كه ميتونه رواز بكنه
I need this. I need to stop being a fraud.
بايد بس كن ، بايد ديه از حقه بازي دست بكشم
I need for once to have something to show for myself.
بايد يه بار هم كه شده سر خودم رو كلاه نزارم
Please, 77. Please.
خواهش ميكنم
- What the fuck you doing? - Jesus!
داري يكار ميكني ؟
Nothing.
هيي
- Don't beat your shit off next to me. - I'm not beating my shit. Fuck off.
دور بر من اين كار رو نكن من هيكاري نكردم ، خفه شو
I'll give you a thousand of my own money.
هزار تا از ول خودم رو بهت ميدم
He should just go.
بايد از اينجا بره
Listen, man, there's insulin in his bag. Can you get it?
ببين ، مرد توي كيفش انسولين هست ميتوني براش بياري ؟
You know that's not allowed.
ميدوني كه اجازه ندارم
I'll give you two. Two thousand.
دوهزار تا بهت ميكنم
Two thousand, man. He needs it.
دوهزار تا مرد ، اون بهش نياز داره
I don't need the money.
من ول نميخوام
Twenty-two. Get up.
بيست و دو . اشو
Captain wants to see you.
كايتان ميخواد ببيندت
Lucky for us, there's no cameras in here.
خوش به حالمون . اينجا دوربين نيست
What?
ي ؟
All right, so if we're going to do this, you can't tell anybody.
خيلي خب ، اه بخوايم اين كار رو بكنيم ، نبايد به كسي بي
The fuck are you talking about?
داري ه ميي ؟
All I want is a blow job. That's it.
بايد يه كار برام بكني
No, no, no, no.
نه ، نــــه
Come on. Just get down on your knees.
بيخيال ، فقط روي زانو هات  خم شو
Yeah. I'm going to go back to my cell...
... آره ، من ميرم به سلول خودم
First, you get down on your knees, all right? All right?
اول ، بايد روي زانوهات خم بشي بعد ، باشه ؟
I want to go back to my cell.
ميخوام برردم به سلولم
You will soon enough. But first you're going to suck my dick.
به زودي ميري اما اول بايد يه كاري برام بكني
Suck it yourself.
م شو
Get down on your knees. Get down on your fucking knees.
بشين روي زانوهات
What's going on in here?
اينجا ه خبره ؟
Nothing.
هيي
What is that prisoner doing out of his cell?
اون اينجا داره يكار ميكنه ؟
He had something to tell me about number 77.
اون يه يزي ميخواست راجب 77 بهم به
He didn't want to say it in front of the others.
نميخواست جلوي شم بقيه حرف بزنه
- Seventy-seven? - Yeah.
هفتاد و هفت ؟ آره
- Is that true? - Yeah, that's true.
درسته ؟
No, I'm asking him. Is that true?
نه ، دارم از اون ميرسم . راست ميه ؟
It's true. It's true.
آره
Barris. Thank God I found you. You got to come quick.
بررس ، خدا رو شكر يدات كردم سريع بيا كارت دارم
See?
مي بيني ؟
Why?
را اخه ؟
What were you doing back there?
اونجا يكار داشتي ميكردي ؟
Nothing.
هيي
I need you to empty your pockets for me then.
س جيب هاتو خالي كن
Empty your pockets, Bosch. Empty that pocket right there.
جيبتو خالي كن ، بوش
You know that nothing from the outside world enters into this cell block.
ميدوني كه هي يزي از بيرون نبايد وارد سلول ها بشه
- You know that, right? - I mean, I was...
ميدوني ، درسته ؟
Quiet. Shut up.
!خــفــه
They're trying to get you to undermine me. I know you would never do that.
اونها دارن كاري مكنن كه تو زير آب منو بزني فكر ميكردم هي وقت همين كاري نميكني
Who asked you to do that?
كي بهت فت همين كاري بكني ؟
You tell me and all will be forgiven.
بهم بو ، و همه ي حله
Who told you?
كي بهت فت ؟
We need to talk later about this.
بعدا راجب اين موضوع باهم صحبت ميكنيم
Later.
تا بعد
As you can see,
... همون طوري كه ميبيني
I'm a reasonable man.
من آدم منطقي هستم
I'm not the monster that you somehow conjured up in your head.
من اون هيولاي نيستم كه تو فكرشو ميكردي
I've been given a position,
من ستي رو رفتم
didn't ask for it.
كه براش درخواستي ندادم
In some ways it would've been easier if I was just a prisoner.
اه من هم مثل تو زنداني بودم يه جورهاي برام آسون تر ميشد
- Like you. - I doubt that very much.
مثل تو خيلي شك دارم
You broke the rules again, 77.
تو دوباره قانون شكني كردي
The guy could've died if he didn't get his insulin...
اون مرد اه انسولين بهش نرسه ميميره
"The guy could've died if he didn't get his insulin."
" اون مرد اه انسولين بهش نرسه ميميره "
Did you hear that?
تو هم شنيدي ؟
A guy could've died if he didn't get his insulin!
!اون مرد اه انسولين بهش نرسه ميميره
Really?
واقعا ؟
When you speak, can you hear yourself?
وقتي صحبت ميكني ، صداي خودتو هم ميشنوي ؟
What do you think is on the other side of those cameras?
فكر ميكني اون طرف دوربين ها ، يه ؟
We are being watched
اونا دارن ما رو نا ميكنن
24 hours a day by people who know what they are doing.
بيست و هار ساعت روز توسط اون آدم ها ، اونا كارشون رو بلدن
Do you think that if there was even a chance, just the littlest bit of a chance,
فكر ميكني اه حتي يه ذره احتمال داشته باشه ... فقط يه ذره
that somebody'd die, that they would let it happen?
كه يه نفري اينجا بميره ... اونها همين جوري ميزات اتفاق بيوفته ؟
He's perfectly safe, your friend.
اون كاملا در محافظته ، دوست رو مم
They will keep him perfectly safe.
اونها كاملا ازش محافظت ميكنن
When this is over, you know what you ought to do?
وقتي آزمايش تموم بشه ، ميدوني بايد يكار بكني ؟
No.
نــه
You ought to take this money,
... ولت رو بير
take a little time off from whatever it is that you do.
و هر كاري كه اينجا كردي رو فراموش كن
Check into a nice, clean mental facility
و خودتو به بيمارستان رواني معرفي كن
where experts can properly diagnose what exactly is wrong with you.
جايي كه اعتمالا دكترها بفهمن تو ه مرته
Maybe you could suggest to me a mental facility,
... شايد بهتره تو يه بيمارستان معرف كني
because obviously you're running around in a mental facility inside of your head.
تو درون خودت مشكل رواني داري واسه همين داري بيمارستان معرفي ميكن
You're letting this guy fucking run the show?
شما ها طور ميزارين اين عوضي رهبري بكنه ؟
You're still not following the rules.
تو همنان داري قانون ها رو زير ا ميزاري
- You need help. - Still arguing about the rules.
تو واقعا به كمك نياز داري همنان داري قانون ها رو رد ميكني
I'm not trying to instigate anything. You need to get help, okay?
من نميخوام مشكلي يش بيارم اما تو واقعا به كمك نياز داري ، باشه ؟
You need some fucking help.
به شدت كمك نياز داري
You know what I need?
ميدوني به ي نياز دارم ؟
I need you to clean that toilet.
من ميخوام تو اون توالت رو تميز كني
- That's what I need. - Enough. Enough of this shit, man.
اين يزه ي كه نياز دارم بسه ديه ، بسه مرد
Toilet! It's not cleaning itself.
!توالت كه خود به خود اك نميشه
Let's just stop this, all right, guys? Let's stop.
ديه تمومش كند اين مسخره بازي رو ، باشه ؟
You're in charge. Does that make you happy?
تو رئيس هستي اين خوشحالت ميكنه ؟
Toilet! I need you to clean my toilet!
!توالت! زود باش توالت منو تميز كن
- Fuck you! - Fuck me?
! لعنت به تو لعنت به من ؟
Fuck. You.
لعنت به تو
I don't normally like to use profanity, but fuck you!
اصولا از فحش دادن خوشم نمياد اما لعنت به تو
You are a prisoner, 77.
تو زنداني هستي ، 77
But your pride is getting in the way.
اما غرورت داره دردسر ساز ميشه
I think I need you to say it for me.
و ازت ميخوام اينو برام تكرا كني
Say, "I am a prisoner."
"بو ، "من زنداني هستم
Fuck you.
لعنت به تو
Say it.
بو
Fuck...
... لعنت
Go to hell.
برو به جهنم
Stop it, please.
بسه ديه ، خواهش ميكنم
Then say it for me.
بو ديه
I...
... من
A prisoner. A prisoner.
زندانيم . زندانيم
A prisoner. I am a prisoner.
زندانيم. من زندانيم
Yes. Yes. Yes, 77.
آزه ، خودشه 77
That is exactly what you are.
دقيقا همون هستي
Hey. Talk to you for a minute?
هي . ميشه يه لحظه باهات صحبت كنم ؟
Come on.
بيا
Let's go.
بريم
- How come we can't talk back in the room? - Some of the guys just wouldn't wait.
طور نميتونيم توي همون اتاق صحبت كنيم ؟ بعضي از افراد نميتون تحمل بكنن
Whatever you guys are going to do, please don't do it.
هركاري كه شماها ميخواين بكنن خواهش ميكنم
I think it's pretty clear by now there will be a zero tolerance for breaking the rules.
فكر كنم ديه تا الان روشن شده باشه براي قانون شكني هي بخششي وجود نداره
Bosch will be joining the prison population.
از اين به بعد بوش به جمع زنداني ها اضافه ميشه
He will be referred to now as Prisoner 76.
و اون شماره ي 76 رو داره
Is there a problem with that, Prisoner 77?
مشكلي هست ، زنداني 77 ؟
Good.
خوبه
I am an equitable man. Equitable. Equitable.
من مرد منصفي هستم
Not once, not once can you accuse me
...شما ها نميتونن منو به قانون شكني "
of breaking the rules.
... متهم كنيد ...
The rules, they help us because they guide us...
اين قوانين به ما كمك ميكنن ... ... ما رو راهنمايي ميكنن
So that we can exist. So that we can exist.
"كه ما بتونين زنده بمونيم ...
Exist in this world.
توي اين دنيا زنده بمونيم
Everybody's not happy with their lot in life.
هي كسي از زنديش راضي نيست
They have a position, he has a position,
اونها براي خودشون جاياهي دارن
and all of you, all of you, you have your positions.
و همه ي شما هم جاياهي دارين
And I, I have a position. Without the rules, there's chaos.
و من هم جاياهي دارم . بدون اين قوانين ، هرج و مرج ميشه
Put that back on.
اون بوش
I said, put that back on, 77.
فتم ، بوشش 77
Did you hear me, 77?
شنيدي ي فتم ؟
Put it back on! You put that back on. You get back in the line.
فتم بوشش برردد توي صف
Don't take another step. What're you doing? Just let him go by? Stop him!
ديه حركت نكن . داري يكار ميكني؟ همين جوري ميزارن بره ؟ جلوشو بيرن
Open the gate. You in there.
درو باز كن . تو اي كه اونجايي
- We're done. - Seventy-seven.
ديه تمومه
You hear me? We're done.
شنيدي ؟
Nobody speaks to them, do you hear me? Nobody.
هي كس با اونها صحبت نميكنه فهميدي ؟ هي كس
Nobody can speak to them. You don't say one single word to them!
هي كس . تو نبايد يه كلمه ديه با هاشون صحبت كني
That's rule number one now. Nobody speaks to them!
اين قانون شماره ي يكه هي كس باهشون صحبت نميكنه
That's my friend!
!اون دوسته منه
You fucking lowlife! You piece of shit!
!زنداني آشغال عوضي
You couldn't just shut the fuck up, could you?
نميتوني فقط دهنتو به ل بيري ؟
You brought this on your fucking self!
!خودت اينو آشغال دوني رو خواستي
Fuck you!
!لعنت به همتون
Divide the prisoners up. Isolate them so they can't communicate.
زنداني ها رو از هم جدا كنيد كاملا ايزولشون بكنيد كه نتونن با هم صحبت بكنن
The only strength in numbers I want inside this place is ours.
فقط ما اينجا رفت و آمد ميكنيم
How the fuck can you listen to that shit? I can't even fucking think.
طور ميتونيد به اين آشغال ها وش بدي ؟ من حتي ديه نميتونم فكرشو بكنم
All I know is I'm out of here.
من ميخوام از اينجا برم
You do know that any decisions we make,
... ميدوني كه تصميم ها رو
we make together?
با هم مييرم ...
Well, this thing's over.
خب ، ديه تمومه
We used violence and the experiment's done.
ما از خشونت استفاده كرديم و آزمايش تمومه
Is it? It's been a lot longer than half an hour and red light hasn't come on yet.
واقعا ؟ الان بيشتر از نيم ساعت شده اما اون راغ هنوز روشن نشده
So fucking what?
خب كه ي ؟
If you think about this rationally, it was the prisoners who did the violence.
اه عاقلانه فكر بكني ، زنداني ها خشونت نشون دادن
We just responded commensurately.
و ما هم به همون اندازهي واكنش نشون داديم
Fuck commensurately. And fuck that fucking red light!
!لعنت به اين اندازت !لعنت به اين راخ قرمز
How can you say that?
طور ميتوني همين يزي بي ؟
The red light, that's the only thing that we have!
اون راغ قرمز ، تنها يزه كه ما داريم
Don't you realize that?
يعني اينو نميفهمي ؟
It's the only way that we can know.
اون تنها يزه ي كه ما رو باخبر ميكنه
Where's my music?
آهن رو روشن كن
You're fucking crazy. You know that?
تو واقعا ديونه اي ، ميدوني ؟
What? Camera? Camera.
ي ؟ يه دوربين
Why? Why would you have...
را ؟
Why don't you stop this? Why?
را جلوشو نمي يري ؟ را ؟
I'll fucking kill you. Kill. I'll fucking kill you.
خودم ميكشمت ، آره من ميكشمت
I'm going to take that tape off of you.
ميخوام اون س رو باز كنم
And you're going to give me what I want. Okay?
و تو اون يزي كه من ميخوام رو بهم ميدي ، باشه ؟
Fuck you.
لعنت به تو
You're a fucking faggot. You know that.
تو واقعا باحال هستي ؟ ميدونستي
Aren't you afraid? Yeah. Yeah.
نميترسي ؟
I know you.
ميشناسمت
You didn't think I would see? You didn't think I was smart enough?
فكر نميكردي ، اينو يدا كنم ؟ فكر نميكردي انقدر زرنم ؟
Please don't hit me again.
لطفا ديه نزن
Hey, I was going to try to be nice.
هي ، ميخوام باهات خوب رفتار كنم
Fucking kill you.
ميكشمت
Please.
خواهش ميكنم
You know, if your mouth doesn't want to play nice,
... اه دهنت خوب بازي نكنه
we'll just have to use the other end.
مجبوريم از جايي ديه استفاده بكنيم
No. No, no, please. Wait, wait. Time out.
نه ، نه ، خواهش ميكنم صبر كن ، صبر كن
- Shut up! - Time out, time out.
خفه شو
No. Please don't do this.
نه ، خواهش ميكنم اين كارو نكن
Hi.
سلام
Go to sleep, motherfucker, go to sleep.
بخواب ، مادر به خطا
You think fags are funny? Who's funny now?
خنده داره ؟ آره ؟
- Hey, kid. You all right? - No. Thank you. Thank you.
به ، حالت خوبه ؟ نه . مرسي ممنون
You still want to go along and get along?
هنوز ميخواي بسوزي و بسازي ؟
Fuck no.
البته كه نه
These boys must think I'm somebody else.
اين به ها فكر ميكنن من يه آدم ديم
Everybody's out, man.
همه بيان بيرون
Hey, buddy. Hey, man.
هي ، رفيق
No, no, no. Come on.
نه ، نه زود باش
Barris, we got trouble.
بررس ، مشكل يش اومده
Coming for you!
!داريم ميايم
Jesus.
يا مسيح
Jesus. What'll we do?
يكار كنيم ؟
We get ready.
آماده ميشيم
You're fucking losing it, man. They outnumber us two to one.
احمق شدي ، مرد اونا دو برابر ما هستن
Maybe, but they're still prisoners. And they're still scared of us.
شايد ، اونها هنوز ندانين و از ما ميترسن
We're the authority here.
ما اينجا قدرت داريم
Does that look like they give a fuck?
به نظرت براشون مهمه ؟
Fuck your authority.
لعنت به قدرتت
What're you doing? What are you doing? We got to stand and fight!
دارين يكار ميكنين ؟ بايد استقامت بكنيم
This is our world! You cannot take it from us! No!
!اين دنياي ماست
Why are you doing this?
را دارين اين كار رو ميكنين ؟
We're still guards! Guards!
!ماهنوز نهبان هستيم
This is your fault!
همش تقير تو بود
You still think we're higher on the evolutionary chain than monkeys?
هنوز فكر ميكني نژاد برتر از ميمون ها هستي ؟
Yeah.
آره
'Cause we can still do something about it.
ون هنوز ميتونيم كارهاي انجام بديم
The facility is actively leased
... اين مركز اجاره شده بوده "
by a corporate think-tank reported to have ties to the government.
و به دولت زارش ميداده ...
A spokesperson with the Monad Corporation
ما با يكي از افرادي كه تحت ... آزمايش بوده صحبت كرديم
tells us the facility has been used for psychological testing.
كه ادعا كردن در اين مكان بر رو اونها آرمايش هاي روانشناسى انجام ميشده
Yes, we'll testify. Whatever it takes.
آره ، ما شهادت ميديم
A guy died in there. A guy named Benjy Putterman.
يكي اونجا مرد يكي به اسم بينجي ورتمن
... arrested the lead researcher, a Dr. John Archalata,
... سر دسته اي اصلي دكتر جان اريتال
and charged him with manslaughter.
به جرم قتل غير عمد دستير شد